As the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua descended from the altar
to minister prayer to the congregation, the fire of the Holy Spirit erupted on the scene.
There was nowhere to hide and nowhere to run from the light of God which searched out
every shade of darkness and affliction, dispelling them with just a touch from God's anointed servant.
Arrested by the power of God, the evil spirits confess their wicked deeds
before being cast out of people's lives across the arena of liberty.
As the ministration continued, this crippled man began to cry out.
Please, Man of God, help me. I can't walk; I am having difficulty in walking.
I use a walking aid to walk.
Please, Man of God, help me - I'm booked for two more surgeries.
I had surgery on my back and I am booked for two more on my cervical and thoracic.
And from my waist downwards is dead. I don't have any feelings at all.
I am wearing a knee brace to help me to walk and a lumbar corset to help me sit up straight.
Man of God, help me.
Prophet T.B. Joshua Ministering
Prayer and Deliverance in Jesus' Name
Man of God, please help me.
Guided by the Holy Spirit, Prophet T.B. Joshua prays for the man in the name of Jesus Christ.
I have no feelings from my waist downward.
The lightning of God pours through the man of God as he prays into the man's injured leg
which begins to lift off the ground and shake uncontrollably as the Spirit of God
strikes the root of the pain and brings instant healing in the name of Jesus Christ.
Stand up!
Walk!
Thank God! Thank You, Lord! Thank You, Jesus!
Thank You, Jesus! I am so happy!
Oh my God! Lord, thank You! I can walk!
TESTIMONY TIME
My name is Charles Ude. I am a Nigerian living in the United States.
Thank you, sir. Who is the gentleman standing next to you?
The next person that is standing next to me is my brother Bernet Ude Eze.
The problem that brought me to The SCOAN was the problem of difficulty in walking.
I had numbness of my leg and that is where it started.
It came from my waist down. It was numb.
I had surgery on my back because of trying to alleviate the problem
but it didn't work so I tried everything; it was not working.
I was using a lumbar corset to sit up straight and a knee brace to help me.
Ok, sir, tell us - how has this problem of numbness and difficulty in walking affected your life in all areas?
It affected my life in everything I do in life.
As a human being, I just couldn't do anything for myself because of that.
It's just like from here alive and this part dead.
So it was very bad and difficult for me.
So truly this problem had crippled you in a very real sense.
Yes, it did.
Ok, so tell us about your career - how was that impacted?
I had stopped working because I couldn't do anything. I was working in the nursing field.
But because of that, I stopped working; for two and a half years, I couldn't do anything.
Just to get better, I was using my vacation hours to get paid till it got depleted.
Then I stopped working completely; then, I went for surgery.
During that time, how would you move around if you needed to go out,
go to a hospital or go to different places?
With the help of my wife and some friends sometimes too and a walking aid to move around.
They even gave me a sticker.
They gave me a sticker to be moving around.
But before that time, I was using the Anointing Water my brother sent to me.
Before that time, before the Anointing Water came...
The first one was sent to me, the pastor where I was worshipping told me,
"It is not good; don't use it".
He kept on telling me to bring it so that we could destroy it.
After a long time, I brought it.
When I brought it out, he then lit it up to burn it.
It was burning.
The water was not putting out the fire as supposed to
but rather it was burning like a spirit with the fire.
And I got scared, and I saw the power of what was being destroyed.
I prayed to God, "Please, God, forgive me for what I have done.
I don't know what I did. Forgive me" and then it burnt completely.
Wow. So I hope we have all understood what our brother is explaining
of how during the course of this problem where he was unable to walk
without the assistance of a walker and without people carrying him at home,
our brother standing next to him, the pastor send the Morning Water
which he had received here at The SCOAN to our brother to be using for his situation.
However, he was discouraged from using the Morning Water by his pastor
back in his country, in the United States that it was not a good thing to use
and when he was eventually deceived into bringing the Morning Water to be destroyed,
instead of when you put fire on the water for it to be quenched, it started burning
as if it was not water inside but instead he saw the power of the Holy Spirit as it was going.
And that convinced him, and that touched his heart to say, "Oh my goodness, I made a big mistake.
I have destroyed a gift of God that God had given to me".
So what happened after then?
So then he send me another one that I was using.
When I started using it, that's when I was able to move around better than I was doing before
and was able to come down here to seek for the face of the Lord.
So just that we can really understand, sir: Describe how you were that time
when your brother send the Morning Water to you before you were able to come to the SCOAN.
How would you move around? How was daily life?
I couldn't move, I couldn't do anything.
I couldn't move without any help unless with my walking aid, knee brace and lumbar corset.
That helped me to move - my walking aid.
Ok. When your brother send the Morning Water and you were able to start using it,
what were the changes you started seeing?
I started having some feelings - a little bit, to move around.
I could get up after I started ministering the Morning Water.
And then I could feel my legs sometimes - trembling a little bit so feelings started coming.
Then, my feet used to burn when I put them on the ground; they used to burn like fire.
And then there was none, it got better.
So it helped me a little bit to come down here.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
Charles Ude & Brother
Healing Testimony
Before we get further, sir, we can see some items on the board there.
Can you tell us what these items are and what they were for.
This on the board here was a handicap sticker that was given to me by the doctors
because they tested my nerves and everything and said I was severely damaged.
Then they gave me this to help me to get closer to the buildings to where I was going.
So when I parked on handicap places, I wouldn't have to walk very far to the buildings.
So this is a sticker only given to people who are diagnosed as handicapped by hospitals.
Exactly.
In order to assist them around the city, to park their car or to be able to move in preference areas.
Exactly; it is true.
Alright and what is the other document?
Now this one here: They booked me for tumor abrasions, for my cervical and thoracic for surgery.
Then I said no.
Then my brother said, "No, don't do anymore surgeries".
Before anymore surgeries, I should come back here and seek the face of the Lord.
Hallelujah! And indeed, we did see you come to The SCOAN last week.
So tell us: What was your experience when the man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua
was moving through the congregation?
Please take time and describe to us when he prayed for you, what was your experience?
He was moving around and I was calling on him to come.
When he finally came to me, he tapped me on the head.
I felt like a shock all over my body and then my body felt light.
And then from my leg - I started having feelings.
Then he started praying for my leg, for the healing.
My leg was kind of moving and then he told me to get up.
When I got up, he then tapped me on the back and he said, "Walk".
I couldn't believe it.
But when I took my first step, second one, I said, "Wow"; I was doing it.
Then I said, "Thank You, Jesus, I am healed". I have been walking ever since then.
I have not taken any medication since that day up till now.
Then, I took medications three times a day. I have not touched them at all.
Come on, put your hands together for Jesus!
If you know that Jesus Christ is going to touch your case just like he touched our brother's life,
let's see your excitement!
So in just that moment, as we are seeing on the screen right now,
we can see the very encounter when Prophet T.B. Joshua prayed for our brother
told him to stand up, tapped him and said, "Walk".
And there he is walking to the glory of God.
So tell us, at that exact moment, when the man of God touched you and loosed the lumbar corset,
and loosed the knee brace, what were you feeling in your leg, feeling in your body?
I started having some feelings going down my legs.
When I touched my legs, I could feel it. Before, I couldn't feel anything.
My children used to stamp on my feet to put life in them.
I didn't feel anything then, no feeling but now, I can feel stuff.
Wow! And then when the man of God now prayed for your leg and it started shaking and moving,
Were you able to move your leg like that before?
No, never. I couldn't even lift my leg one inch off the ground but I can do this now.
Let us put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So you mean it was impossible for you to be moving your legs like this, sir, before the prayer?
I couldn't do it. One inch off the ground, I could not lift.
It would be like I was lifting 10 bags of cement.
Wow! And now here you are exercising.
We want to also ask you, sir, to do some exercises right now, to stand up and walk
and show the people of God what you can do after the prayer of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
Charles Ude & Brother
Healing Testimony
There he goes marching like a soldier; you can see him walking easily now.
This is what was impossible for him to do for the past several years
because of this problem of numbness, and pain from the waist
that had caused him to be bed ridden, giving him severe difficulty in walking.
Sir, as you are moving around, as you are walking,
how are you feeling? Is there any pain or problem?
Not really, no. It feels great walking around.
You are healed.
Yes, I am healed, in Jesus' name.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus!
Hallelujah! We want to hear a word of advice from you in a moment but before then,
we would like to hear from the gentleman that came with you.
Si,r you are welcome, in Jesus' name.
Please introduce yourself to us and the congregation.
Emmanuel!
(God with us - Matthew 1:23)
Brethren, my name is Pastor Ben Eze Udeze.
I'm from Enungu, Nigeria.
The Founder of Calvary Love Ministry.
Praise the Lord.
Hallelujah!
Charlie is my brother; he called me and told me that he wasn't feeling fine.
I said, "Wow, what's the problem?"
He said his leg could not raise up and he would undergo surgery.
I asked, "Surgery?" and he said, "Yes".
I said, "Okay".
The US is far different from Nigeria.
I told him I would go and talk to my father in the Lord, Prophet T.B. Joshua
and truly, I came here and received the Morning Water.
I sent it to him; praise the Lord!
When I sent the first one to him, he said that the pastor of the church he was attending
told him to bring the Morning Water to him, that it is not of God.
Then, he gave it to him and he set it on fire.
And the thing could not burn.
They thought that the water would quench the fire but it failed.
What he saw there was that the water was working as if there was something on it - Spirit.
Praise the Lord!
Then, that one was gone just like that.
Then after that, I sent him another one.
That one enabled him to come out of pain.
Then I told him that it was high time he came back to Nigeria,
that he wouldn't need surgery anymore because we have a fire house in Nigeria.
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So this was what convinced your brother that "Oh, this was a mistake!
What I actually needed is what I have now destroyed". Is that right?
Yes, that propelled me to give him another one.
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah.
Amen.
Pastor Ben Eze Udeze & Brother
Healing Testimony
I told him to come down and he came.
I told him, "Let's go to the House of God", and he followed me just like that.
We came here and the man of God touched him.
Death left him; life entered automatically.
Praise the Lord!
Life entered automatically.
There is God here.
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
You are seeing on the screen right now the very moment
where Prophet T.B. Joshua touched our brother in the name of Jesus Christ
and the life of God began to enter every part of his system
that had been dead, damaged and dormant and there he is walking for the glory of God.
Let's put our hands together for Jesus once again!
Yes.
So since then, sir, what have been the changes you have noticed in our brother.
My brother has been walking with me.
When we entered the plane to come here, I was not happy, seeing him with a crutch
but now, I am smiling; I am feeling free.
I have confidence because I came to the mountain of God, not mountain of man.
The mountain of man faileth but the mountain of God stands sure.
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah! Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
So, sir, now seeing what God Almighty has done in the life of your brother,
what is your word of advice to people watching all over the world?
Wow! People of God, the whole world watching me right now,
I say, let us go to the House of God.
Let us go; forget about the protocols you have or problem you may have.
The solution is here in the arena of liberty; let's go!
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah! Put your hands together for Jesus!
A wonderful word of advice that no matter what problem you have,
the solution is only with our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ
who works in every one of his living churches all over the world.
So make sure you find a living church and run to God whenever you have a problem,
instead of running from Him. Let's put our hands together for Jesus once again!
Lastly, we want to hear a word of advice from our brother who received his wonderful healing today.
Sir, tell us your advice to people watching all over the world.
People of God, whatever problem you have, my advice is:
Whatever problem you are having in this world, no matter what it is,
don't run from God, run to Him; there is solution there.
Regardless of what it is, whatever you are going through,
run to God, don't run away from Him.
Running away from Him is the biggest mistake you make in your life.
That's what I have to say.
Amen. Let's put our hands together for Jesus Christ!
A sound word of advice and, sir, we thank God Almighty for this wonderful healing you have received
and we encourage you: You have been healed through the Word of God.
So continue to make God's Word the standard for your life
and this healing shall remain permanent, in Jesus' name.
Amen!
Two weeks after his healing, Mr Ude is not only strong physically but spiritually as well.
Before going back to the US, to his surprise,
Prophet T.B. Joshua supports Mr Ude with a financial gift as well.
Let's watch.
My name is Charles Ude. I am a Nigerian living in USA.
Thank you, sir, and who is the gentleman standing next to you?
That is my brother Bennett Eze.
The problem that brought me to The SCOAN was the problem of difficulty in walking.
Then, I had a lumbar corset I was using that helped me sit up straight, stand up straight
and do a lot of stuff that I couldn't do well.
Even though I was wearing it, it was not helping me.
I was wearing a knee brace.
I used to have a walking aid to help me move around a little bit.
The problem affected my daily life so much that I could not do anything.
I had two little children - 5 and 3.
I couldn't even play with them. I couldn't even teach them how to ride bikes.
I could not do anything for them
and the children didn't understand what was going on with daddy.
When Prophet T.B. Joshua touched me and prayed for me,
I was able to get up and started walking.
Ever since then, I have been walking and walking around.
I never want to stop walking around because it is something that I never thought I could...
The devil would deny me walking.
But now through the help of the man of God, I have been healed and walking around.
Glory be to God. I thank God for using the man of God to help me.
Amen! To God be the glory. So since the man of God has prayed for you,
how many days has it been and what are the changes you have seen?
It's going to two weeks now.
The changes have been tremendous.
I just can't explain; there are no words to explain the entire changes,
that I have been getting from this - the happiness, everything about it.
Even people that know me, when they see me, they say, "Oh your face is glowing right now..
It's just too much. It's unimaginable.
I'm so happy about it.
Wow! To God be the glory!
Well, that's it. The Bible promises us that the evidence of Jesus Christ is lives changed
and you are telling us your life has changed to the glory of God.
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
I am Pastor Ben Eze.
Before, he could not walk but since he came here, after the man of God touched him,
healing entered, life entered and now, he has started walking.
He can walk with me; we have stayed here almost two weeks and he has been walking.
I feel happy; I feel joy. Glory be to God!
Amen! And as a minister of the Gospel, how has this impacted on your faith,
seeing what God has done to someone close to you?
Beautiful! It has encouraged me that walking in the way of God is the most important thing.
God called me but it is not like this; I am seeing this, it has propelled me high
with the hope that God has something to do with me tomorrow.
Praise the Lord!
Hallelujah! Thank you very much, sir.
And lastly, what is your word of advice to people watching all over the world
who are in a position you were in, to be of help and assistance to someone in need?
I have friends outside and inside - I have been calling them, telling them that they should come.
There is power in the house.
I told a lot of them, "Let us go to Emmanuel TV - there is something happening,
miracles are happening and you can see God in His nature here".
Praise the Lord! Let us go; it is good. Amen.
Amen! Thank you very much. What a wonderful comment, sir.
So let's hear from our brother once again. Mr Charles.
His word of advice to people all over the world
who has seen what the power of God has done in his life.
My advice is: No matter what you are going through, look for the face of God.
Disregard what people are saying about the face of God,
especially Emmanuel TV and Prophet T.B. Joshua.
That man is a lion.
That man - God uses him in so many ways;
in so many ways that you can't even imagine.
He is in everything, helping everybody.
He doesn't care how big you are or how small you are.
He sees everybody equal.
The man is great.
I thank God and my advice is: Whatever you are going through, look for the face of God.
What is your plan for the future? What is the next step for you?
My plan is to go back to the USA where I came down from and continue from where I left off.
And with the prayers the man of God has given me,
I believe he has opened all the doors of greatness for me.
So I know the sky is my limit right now.
I know that progress won't stop coming.
It's going to be coming from everywhere, from all angles, in Jesus' name.
It is our pleasure to present you on behalf of Prophet T.B. Joshua and Emmanuel TV Partners
the sum of N150 000 as financial support and a copy of The Mirror.
Wow! Thank God and I thank God for Emmanuel TV.
I came to get healing, I got healing.
Not only did I get healing, I also got financial support to support me.
God is great and I pray to God to continue to use Prophet T.B. Joshua
to help so many people and touch so many lives and change so many lives all over the world.
And Emmanuel TV Partners to continue to do the good work they do.
God uses them in so many ways regardless of who you are.
I thank God and I thank Emmanuel TV for everything they have done for me.
He healed me and then he also gave me financial support.
To God be the glory. Amen!
Emmanuel!
(God With Us - Matthew 1:23)
Thank You, Jesus!
TT Monica Asefa 30/01/19
RV: Mel Flowers 10/02/2019